More formally, here are the steps we'll take to calculate the Rank IC.
下面介绍计算排名 IC 的正式步骤
For each time period,
对于每个时段
rank the raw Alpha factor.
对原始 Alpha 因子进行排名
For instance, with a stock universe of three stocks,
例如 假设股票池有三个股票
the lowest Alpha value has a rank of 1,
Alpha 值最低的股票排名为 1
and the highest Alpha value has a rank of 3.
Alpha 值最高的股票排名为 3
Also, calculate the forward asset returns and rank them.
然后计算远期资产收益率并排名
The stock with the lowest forward return has a rank of 1,
远期收益率最低的股票排名为 1
and the stock with the highest forward return has a rank of 3.
远期收益率最高的股票排名为 3
The correlation of ranked values is called
排名值的相关性称为
the Spearman rank correlation to distinguish it from the Pearson correlation.
斯皮尔曼等级相关系数 与皮尔逊相关系数区分开
Let's clarify these two terms.
我们解释下这两个术语
The Pearson correlation is what you're probably familiar with,
你可能熟悉皮尔逊相关系数
is the covariance of two variables which is then
它是指两个使用二者标准差
re-scaled using the standard deviations of the two variables.
重新调整范围的两个变量之间的相关性
The denominator makes the correlation range from negative 1 to 1.
分母使相关性范围从 -1 到 1
The Pearson Correlation is also the square root of the R-squared in a linear regression.
皮尔逊相关系数在线性回归中也是 R^2 的平方根
Recall that the R-squared represents the proportion of
R^2 表示一个变量中
variance in one variable that is explained by the second variable.
由另一个变量解释的方差比例
The Spearman rank correlation is the same as the Pearson correlation,
斯皮尔曼等级相关系数与皮尔逊相关系数一样
except the variables x and y are converted to
但是在计算协方差和标准差之前
ranks before calculating the covariance and standard deviations.
先将变量 x 和 y 变成排名
To get the rank IC,
为了获取排名 IC
calculate the correlation between the ranked Alpha vector
我们需要计算单个时期的排名 Alpha 因子
and the ranked forward asset returns for a single time period.
与已排名远期资产收益率之间的相关性
Repeat this over multiple time periods to get a time series.
针对多个时段重复这一流程并获得时间序列
You may be wondering why we use
你可能会疑问
the Spearman rank correlation as opposed to the Pearson correlation.
为何使用斯皮尔曼等级相关系数 而不使用皮尔逊相关系数
That is why do we use ranking?
为何要使用排名数据？
The answer is because we don't care about being wrong in the right direction.
因为我们对方向错误不关心
Let's say stock ABC is our top Alpha value in a universe of 2,000 stocks.
假设在有 2,000 支股票的股票池中 股票 ABC 的 Alpha 值最高
Our alpha value will likely be a small positive value,
Alpha 值很可能是个很小的正值
then imagine that ABC outperforms all the other stocks not by a small amount,
假设 ABC 超过所有其他股票很多很多
but by a very large amount.
而不是很小的量
The Pearson correlation would calculate a lower score
皮尔逊相关系数的分数更低
effectively penalizing us because we didn't get the relative magnitude correct.
因为我们计算的相对大小不正确
On the other hand, the Spearman rank correlation would not be affected by this.
而斯皮尔曼等级相关系数不受影响
We prefer to use ranking to evaluate our performance because
我们喜欢使用排名来评估业绩
what matters is that our Alpha is still profitable as we had hoped.
是因为重要的是 Alpha 依然能像我们期望的那样获利